Abel Rajesh

23 Cuil Duin Way Citywest Dublin 24 089 495 8035

<u>abel.rajesh2@mail.dcu.ie</u> <u>https://github.com/abelraj20?tab=repositories</u>

Personal Profile

Third-year Physics with Data Analytics student at Dublin City University who is extremely motivated and on course to acquire a 1.1. Developed skills in the use of MS Office, Microsoft OS, Python and SQL through completing various college projects. Gained experience in both planning and executing desired tasks while adhering to strict deadlines. Prospered strong teamwork and communication skills through engagement in multiple group projects and working part-time.

Education

Dublin City University
Bachelors in Physics with Data Analytics (Expected grade: 1.1)

2022 - present

Relevant Modules: Digital and Analogue Electronics, Advanced Programming, Databases and Data Visualisation, Semiconductor Physics, Machine Learning

Project(s):

Kolmogorov Flow: Performed a study on Kolmogorov flow by focusing on factors such as Lagrangian particle tracking, Reynold's number and Vorticity. Delegated tasks of project design, experimentation, data analysis and programming among team members. Developed a design for the project equipment on Blender and used soldering tools to create equipment. Utilised Raspberry Pi Camera to record data and python library trackpy for data analysis. Implemented image processing techniques on recorded video frames to extract meaningful data.

Principal Component Analysis (PCA): Implemented a machine learning approach using feature extraction to cluster a multi-variable iris dataset into the iris species: Setosa, Versicolor and Virginica. Standardised the dataset and computed matrices to extract eigenvectors and eigenvalues. Utilised python libraries (matplotlib, NumPy, pandas and seaborn) for data analysis and visualisation. Plotted principal components with the highest variance to differentiate between iris species. Delivered findings through a PowerPoint presentation to peers and professors during an exhibition.

Rockbrook Park School, Dublin Leaving Certificate: 542 Points 2016 - 2022

Languages: Spanish and Irish

Skills/Achievements

- Proficiency in Python, SQL, HTML and CSS
- Git and GitHub
- Expertise in MS Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint)
- Knowledge of MS Outlook, Teams and OneDrive
- Data preprocessing and visualisation
- Experience with laboratory instrumentation
- Received full driver's licence in 2023
- Represented South Dublin and received 3 medals in Irish International Taekwondo Competitions
- Completed grade four in guitar with Trinity College London

Work History

Uniphar Group, Dublin 24 Warehouse Operative

July 2022 - Present (p/t)

- Collaborated with supervisors and colleagues to confirm operations ran smoothly
- Catalogued general stock and ensured the placement of items in designated areas
- Conducted routine inspections of incoming and outgoing pharmaceuticals
- Cleaned and maintained warehouse to keep a safe workplace environment

Cheeverstown Nursing Home Caregiver

November 2019 - December 2019

- Managed and updated residents' medical records with accurate and timely entries
- Collaborated with the healthcare team to implement individualised care plans
- Co-ordinated with mobility and physical therapy exercises
- Maintained clean and sanitary living environments to ensure health and safety

Interests

- Play guitar as a hobby and also teach children in the local community
- Active member of energie fitness gyms, attend four times each week
- Practice Taekwondo for three years and have competed in national competitions
- Practice swimming in Tallaght leisure centre, attend once every week
- Member of DCU judo club, attend once every week

Languages

- Intermediate proficiency in Spanish and Irish from secondary level education
- Fluency in Malayalam as it is my native language

References

Available on Request